if you want a simple and high reward way
to trade then continuation trading might
be for you in this class I'm going to
break down what continuation trading
even is how you can do it and how you
can basically ride any Trend until it
ends to catch multiple winning traits in
a very simple approach to trading we're
not going to waste any time so let's get
straight into the lessons the first
thing to understand is exactly what we
mean when we say continuations so this
class is geared around continuation
trading not reversals now A reversal
would be pretty much anywhere within
this area of price action where we see
the market shifting from higher highs
and higher lows into lower lows and
lower highs the reversal trading
opportunities would come potentially up
here potentially in here and most
commonly in here where we're basically
taking advantage of this first shift in
the market to enter into a reversal into
the start of a new trend but that's not
the focus of today's video continuations
are continuations are pretty much every
other piece of price action that you can
see here simply put it's continuing
through the trend so this would be a
continuation trading phase and so would
this second point just here so we can
eliminate the reversal and the
continuation areas that we're looking at
today and the systems that you're going
to be following and learning about in
today's class is to trade continuations
through existing trending moves so
during this move where the structure is
continually breaking into new highs our
trades will be
from the lows that we form in this
uptrend so we're simply continuing the
direction of the trade eventually when
the trend does come to an end and shift
Direction this will be a phase of
reversal trading which we won't be
involved in in fact likely we will be
involved in it we will probably get into
a trade at one of these points and then
potentially lose one of our positions as
the market reverses the idea with
continuations is not to be right on
every single trade as it's not with any
other of trading but it will allow us to
be right multiple times before we are
finally wrong so if we continue to move
with an existing Trend the only time
that a loss is really going to come
through for the most part is when the
market reverses on us so if we were to
buy from here we would be abruptly
stopped out of this trade we would lose
and that would be fine we would then
lead into a new phase of continuation
trading which in the downward Trend
would be looking to sell the highs that
we form so continuations are existing
trend trending moves and just catching
trades through moves that are already
taking place so this phase here is
bullish continuation this phase is
bearish continuation and this area in
the center is reversal trading which is
not what we're going to be looking at
today okay so that is the basis of what
continuations are now let's take a look
at the entry models that we'll use to
actually trade in this manner okay so
here's a look at the entry model that
we're going to be using to get into
continuation trades now we can see the
overall premise of this idea is that
we'll be taking this inside of a
downtrend okay so we would need this to
come from a bearish continuation move we
are first looking for a break of
structure into a continuation in the
downtrend then we are looking for a pull
back to bring us back to an area of
Supply we're going to show you this in a
moment you'll see how Supply zones work
and you'll see how we're going to be
using these for entries uh on a real
chart once the market reacts to the
supply Zone which is basically a
consolidation area that created the
large downward move that we are trading
from we are then looking at entering in
one of two ways the first way is what we
can call a risk entry a risk entry is
where we just sell limit so an order
that will immediately enter you into a
sell when the market hits the supply
Zone if you sell limit here your stop
loss will then go above the previous
lower high and this way unless the
market changes trending Direction on you
you are not going to lose a trade so
you'll only lose if the market reverses
and inv validates your setup this way is
a good way to trade it's very very
simple you simply find the trending
Direction and then you place your order
and allow the market to either run in
your favor and you win the trade or if
it turns on you this actually confirms a
change into a high so then you can start
to trade the uptrending movement
providing that continues through now the
second way to trade is with a fractal
confirmation so take a look at this area
here we're basically seeing a small
reversal format we have a high High
higher low higher high and then the
market breaks down into a lower low and
then we are looking to sell this point
here or the first lower high that is
really formed within this trending move
so here we actually use a small reversal
to trade inside of the larger
continuation movement what this does is
validate that this smaller price action
is now also in a downtrend if we picture
what we see here we have a high lower
low lower high so we know that this
phase of price action is now bearish if
we pair that with the fact that the
larger phase of price action that we're
trading is also bearish we basically get
an extra layer of Confirmation and
Clarity that the market is likely to
move in our Direction now there are some
things to note about these two different
ways of trading if you trade the sell
limit approach this approach here you
are going to miss way less trades
because sometimes the market isn't going
to come in for that fractal confirmation
which means that we may just do this and
the trade that you were looking to take
from the area of refined Supply is not
going to get hit in an instance where
this happens of course this is going to
be a missed opportunity but the entry
here will be secured so you're going to
catch pretty much every trade that you
do see you're not going to have such a
concern about missing out on
opportunities however due to the fact
that we are not refining with this
example here our risk reward is going to
be slightly lower if we take a look at
these two entry models the risk reward
of the first is 4.72 the potential for
the second is 8.4 so we actually get
around 2x The Profit potential on this
setup than we do on the initial the sell
limit setup so you're kind of balancing
there between higher risk reward most of
the time on the confirmation based
entries but the opportunity to miss
trades also on the confirmation based
entries now the other thing is of course
because you are working with additional
confirmation you'll have higher win
rates for the trades that you do catch
so you might only catch 50% % of the
trades using confirmations that you
would have caught if you used the sell
limit entry but you're probably going to
win a reasonable percentage more because
when you sell limit into every Zone you
are open to the fact that the market may
just completely reverse on you where
you'll get stopped out once your stop
loss is here if you're waiting for this
confirmation the chances of that
happening are considerably lower now yes
of course sometimes the market will
trick you into a sell and then just
break higher anyway so you will still
lose some trades here this is not a
guarantee
kind of Magic Bullet way to win every
single setup but you will pretty
drastically increase the amount of
Trades that do work out it just means
that you're going to miss a few trades
as well so what we're going to do is
back test both of these approaches in
real markets before we do that I'm going
to just jump over to the charts and show
you a real example of this and then
we'll run through a little back test and
I'll show you the comparative results
between this approach and this approach
let's get to it okay so here would be a
solid example of a continuation trade
using a confirmation based entry so the
secondary format that we mentioned now
we can see this Market is in a downtrend
right we're continually forming lower
lows and lower highs just to zoom that
out a bit basically from this high
downwards we are making clear bearish
movements there are three different
concepts realistically that we're going
to be using inside of this system number
one is Market structure that is just the
idea that if the market is continually
forming lower lows and lower highs that
it's in a downtrend or if it's forming
higher highs and higher lows that it's
in an uptrend to mark that on this chart
that we're currently looking at we have
a high breaking into a low here this is
kind of the first sign that we're moving
into a downtrend and then we have this
low breaking into new lows from there
onwards and you can see that this is our
high but this is a lower high and then
this is potentially another lower high
which is where we would ideally be
looking to sell now the market structure
is purely for directional bias once we
have our directional bias in mind the
other two concepts we need to consider
are market efficiency and supply and
demand so market efficiency refers to
open price ranges now if we take a look
at this phase of price action just this
small upward moving movement here we
don't have any open price ranges we
initially begin with this candle the
market then pushes up a little but we
have a wick that fills the range so
let's neaten this up a little bit
basically what we see here is that we
have have this slow chop right and
basically every area that opens up is
retested by price so there's no
significant open in Balance right until
we get to this point here so this area
between basically this candle and these
candles up here we see that where I've
just marked out these red lines between
here is an open price range that's what
we call the imbalance and imbalance is
important because we always want to see
these imbalances filled so if we take a
look back here between this candle in
this candle we have the imbalance now
I'm not looking to sell from inside of
an imbalance I don't think that makes
too much sense I know there's a way of
trading that called fvs but I prefer to
see and we do very often see the
imbalance completely filled which means
if the market trades back up against
that imbalance like it did here we would
expect the market to come all the way to
the top of the imbalance before then
reversing and you can see that that's
what's happened in this example just
here right so we always want to see the
imbalance filled and to identify an
imbalance we are just looking for an
open price range which realistically is
just a price range that has been opened
in the market that has no further Wicks
or anything leading into it so just to
give you some examples this area between
this candle and this candle is not an
imbalance because this Wick here filled
the imbalance and as you can see it
didn't trade from the imbalance it
pushed above the imbalance and then sold
off this area just here is an imbalance
at this point in time after we had this
selloff but now it is no longer
imbalance because the market came back
up and retested the area above the
imbalance okay if we take a look at the
existing current trending movement then
from this to this this is an imbalance
okay so we would anticipate at some
point for the market to come up trade
over the high of the imbalance range and
then trade lower so that's the concept
of Market efficient because another name
for these imbalances that we see in the
market is an inefficiency right
efficient markets are like what we first
looked at where we have these clear
choppy markets that have Wicks filling
in every single one of the open price
ranges an inefficient range or an
imbalanced range is where we don't have
any Wicks and we just have one large
open candle or a few large open candles
that haven't yet been filled in yet that
is the next concept we need to be aware
of now the final concept we need to be
aware of for trading this strategy is
going to be supply and
demand now a supply zone is basically an
area of consolidation before a large
down move this big wick candle here
small candle body Wick Wick shows a
consolidation if we were to see this on
a lower time frame it's generally going
to show that we opened at this level we
attempted to go higher we attempted to
go lower and then we closed around the
same level that we opened at okay that's
why we have this small candle body and
this big push up and this push down are
the attempts to go higher and lower
before the market readjusted and closed
near its open price so this would be our
consolidation before the large downward
move and we want to connect this Wick to
Wick to make sure we have the full range
covered so this would be our supply zone
now if we pair everything together we
have a supply Zone with an imbalance
leading into it and we have a clear
downward trending market so because we
are seeing a downtrend we only want to
sell and we only want to sell then once
the imbalance is filled and and the
supply Zone has been retested as we've
seen just here now there is one thing
worth noting about this trade we
wouldn't really want to sell limit this
trade so the first of the two entry
criterias I showed you would be risky
for this position it's not great for two
reasons number one is the risk reward if
we were to sell here and we had a stop
above the high we'd have to have a
pretty big Target to get any meaningful
risk reward realistically I want to get
at minimum 3 to1 reward to risk ratio so
I need to make sure I'm risking $1 to
make $3 or more I don't want to do any
less than that so aside from having to
have and being forced into having a
large stop loss on this position the
other problem we have is that when we
talked about the imbalance if we were to
take a look at the price move above we
can see that we actually have got some
more imbalance higher in the price range
so if we sell limit here at this level
there is every opportunity that we come
up towards this point but we continue
trading higher until the imbalances are
filled and the market approaches Supply
zones up here we could then sell off
from this point which would be totally
valid but it means that if we sell limit
here at this first area we're opening
ourselves up to potential double losses
or potentially taking a loss
unnecessarily essentially before a
winning trade comes through so rather
than using a direct sell limit approach
into this Market we would prefer to use
the confirmation based approach now that
we've had this hourly Supply Zone retest
we can actually take a look just up here
and we see that we have the this
consolidation candle I always use the
last candle before the impulse to Mark
supply and demand before a large bearish
impulse to the downside if we then
consider the structure inside of this
smaller range we can see that there has
been a break of structure around this
point here where the market is now
shifted from higher highs and higher
lows into a lower low so a better way to
approach this trade would be with that
fractal confirmation approach that we've
already covered and it's actually formed
now at this point we could place our
cell limit on this Supply Zone we could
place our stop loss above for around
10.5 Pips and then we can determine our
Target and to determine targets we'll
actually take a look over to the left
and identify reasonable price areas that
the market could come into so we're
looking for previous swing lows and
areas of demand areas of liquidity so
for simplicity's sake we're going to
take a look at this swing low first of
all and see what this would look like in
terms of risk reward for a position this
is probably going to be a reasonably
lowrisk reward we're getting just under
a 3:1 so if we target that low we're
getting just under a 3:1 if we put our
stop to the high little bit down 10.2
Pips which is still clearing the high
still a valid trade we've actually
improved our risk reward to that 3:1
ratio okay now obviously in a real
example we may look for extended targets
so we may look to refine a way to get a
tighter entry but because I'm just
showing you the overall basis of the
trade and the elements we'll be using I
think this is fine for the example so
let's just recap on what we've got we
have a predominantly downtrending Market
we then have an imbalance or an
inefficient price range which was formed
just here this imbalance was then filled
when the market moved up towards this
area and by running up to this area it
traded into the supply Zone which is an
area that we're expecting significant
movements to occur from in line with the
overall bearish trend so we have the
first bearish movement pullback to fill
inbalance retest of Supply we are now
looking for that confirmational shift
and that is exactly what we've seen at
this point here so using the path tool
we can Mark out this smaller Trend we've
got this higher high higher low
structure then we've broken down into a
lower low now we can look for pullbacks
to sell into this market and our Target
is just a simple swing low that hasn't
been filled yet so we can anticipate
that the market will be likely to lead
into there now there is another way we
can find Targets and that is just simply
to attack the local swing low so that
would mean you would take profits there
but obviously for a trade like this
where we can't get massive risk reward
out of it it would be better to go for
an extended Target I'm sure we will see
some examples of this during the back
test though so you can see now that
whole entry criteria that we just marked
up before moving over to this real chart
has now aligned we have a bearish trend
a filled imbalance a retested supply
Zone and now we've started breaking into
that fractal confirmation seeing the
lower time frame agree with the high
time frame so what we can do now is just
flick this Market forward a little bit
and you'll see how it hands out you see
we come up trade into the area of supply
and then pretty quickly sell all the way
down to our Target level so our trade
would have been executed about 1 hour
after we prepped the setup and then 5
hours after we entered we have filled
the target for a potential 3% return if
you were risking 1% on this setup which
is generally uh the standard amount of
risk per trade so that is an idea as to
how we actually follow through this
confirmation entry criteria and this
continuation entry criteria we see
downtrend or if we were going the other
way we'd look at an uptrend we want to
see a new imbalance form we want to see
that imbalance filled we want to see a
demand zone or Supply Zone retest
depending on whether we're buying or
selling and when we get that retest we
then want to see the fractal
confirmation to provide the actual entry
for us which allows us to number one
refine our stop- loss and number two get
the safest possible entry that is what
the trade looks like in reality now
let's go and do some back testing all
right so we're looking at AUD CAD here
on the hourly and I've just located a
trade we have a supply Zone just here uh
this would be a good entry for the sell
limit style entry so let me break this
actual kind of context down for you as
we know we want to look at three things
the trending Direction This is a
downtrending market it actually
continues downtrending in the past we
have imbalance the imbalanced price
range that we're looking at here is this
candle as you can see this is an open
price range there is no Wick or body or
anything that currently fills this range
so basically Above This high that we've
just printed on the hourly and below
this area of Supply that's the imbalance
range in between there now obviously the
third thing then is the supply Zone
that's where we want to get in the
supply zone is this candle this
indecision candle or consolidation
candle before the large downward move
this shows institutional levels of
selling entering the market at this
point that is why we get this big Drive
Lower we are just looking to join that
flow seeing this as a premium price area
that Traders were happy to sell at
before we would expect that they will be
happy to sell here again now for this
trade we're going to keep things nice
and simple this is the most simplistic
way to approach continuations for your
Target because the risk reward allows us
to we can simply Target this low here
okay so this would mean if we do get
tapped in we are just looking to take
the market down towards this area this
next low in the trend the reason that
this trade is now set up as a good
continuation opportunity is because if
we get tapped in here we would expect
the market to trade lower due to the
fact that we are in an overall downtrend
if however the market doesn't do that
and it pushes higher our stop loss will
get us out of this trade without taking
a major loss because as soon as this
High breaks we're pretty much wrong on
this position so as long as our stop is
positioned there we're minimizing the
downside we can take but if the market
does play to our plan this is an easy
target because it's obviously the next
in the downtrend if the downtrend
continues this target will be hit and we
get a massive risk reward profile so we
actually can make $
8.53 for every $1 we risk here so if you
were to do this with a $1,000 risk it
could potentially return
8,530 back to you so what we're going to
do now is place this order inside of the
simulation so we need a sell limit order
we're going to save that and here is our
entry if the market comes into this area
of Supply we will be tapped in now we
are also going to monitor for the
confirmation style approach as well okay
we're going to do that for any trade
that we do take through this phase of
downward trending price action see if we
can get confirmations for these trades
as well so we've just pushed down we've
had a very light break of structure here
underneath this previous low this is a
closure so this would now be valid to
place a sell limit at this Supply zone
so here we've actually had that
confirmational shift that we want we
could place a sell limit here and we we
would have our stop loss Above This high
and our Target down towards the same
Target we were looking for on trade
number one now for these confirmation
based entries I don't want to double
stack position so I'm not actually going
to place an order for this one we're
just going to monitor and see how it
plays out okay let's allow the market to
run then and see if we get a fill on
that second
opportunity we can allow the market to
run for a bit we would only have to step
in and identify potential for later
executions now we have two potential
working zones so we can leave the
initial sell limit trade to run but for
the confirmation entry opportunity we
have this Supply which we were happy to
place a sell limit on but we've now
formed a new Supply just here this new
Supply obviously has driven price even
lower this is great news for our sell
limit but if you're using the
confirmation approach you won't be in
just yet so this would be an ideal
situation to join the trade with
confirmations but the risk is now the
market could potentially push and drive
higher towards this point which would
mean a sell limit here could easily be
stopped out even if the trade is correct
now the reason I don't like to take
positions like this is because if the
market is to go all the way up not only
do we take one loss here but we're also
going to lose this position too so we've
turned what was a good idea into two
losses which is not ideal so what I
would do at this point is look for
something we call fractal confirmation
as we've seen so far with this Market
shifting from higher highs and higher
lows into lower lows and ideally now
into a lower high we're going to look
for this exact same format but on a
smaller scale inside of here so we can
monitor the pullback towards here and if
we get opportunity to enter we will if
we don't we will hold our sell limit
order at the top Zone understanding that
a market pull back to there could
provide us with the opportunity that we
want to get into a trade so let's
eliminate this for now because this is
not something that we're going to have
on at this point in time okay so we've
now seen the first signs that we want to
see we've seen our high higher low
higher high it's only a wick we can't
use this to validate Longs but we can
use it to indicate that a higher high
has been printed and now we would want
to see this low broken this would
provide that confirmation entry that
we're looking for to highlight that it's
going to be this movement okay that is
what we want to see then we will sell
from Supply if we get a pullback so this
just makes our trade a little a little
bit safer if we approach in this manner
we are going to get the highest
probabilities and we're not going to get
ourselves into bad losing trades here we
can see we have Supply we do have a bit
of a wick there but there is still
notable imbalance between the current
candle and the supply zone so this would
definitely be a fine place for us to go
and place our cell limit now you can
also go and do Zone refinement which is
where you'd go to a lower time frame
like the in this instance 30 minute but
we're just going to keep it simple cuz
we're just highlighting the theories
here so we have our confirmation we're
going to not place this order as we've
said but we will track how this one
works out at this point because we're
placing a new order we can delete that
one we're going to clear this one to
keep it simple at this point we can see
our cell limit position is running
pretty profitably we have
$2,971 in unrealized profits at the
moment which is around 3% and if we get
tagged on this confirmation
trade as we have now that would be the
potential confirmation or fractal
confirmation way to get into this trade
so now let's run the market a little bit
faster both positions are executed so we
don't really need to take our time with
it at this point of course you are
moving with the overall higher time
frame flow of the market so the best
thing you can do is just leave the
market to print its lows and just let it
do its own thing there is no reason now
to be rushing into opportunities you can
just allow the market to flow okay you
don't need to rush in you don't need to
panic and get out you can just allow
these trades to flow through because if
the trending direction is correct that
you formulated the trade around then you
are going to be in for a winning trade
there's no worry about that okay so the
take profit was hit on both of these and
now let's take a quick look at the
performance of both opportunities the
first one is the sell limit opportunity
remember what we said about these you
are going to have lower
probability of winning because you are
not working with confirmations but you
are also going to have higher trade fre
frequency so basically pretty much every
trade that you find you will be able to
execute or the majority of them because
you just get in as soon as Supply or
demand is tapped so you get a higher
trade frequency overall meaning more
wins but also more losses now if you
have a higher risk tolerance this is a
good approach because you're going to
get more trades you'll win every trade
that does work out and you'll be able to
mentally manage the losses that do form
as well for for most people though a lot
of people are a bit timid around trading
especially when trying to learn and get
into this so This confirmational
approach may be the better one for you
now this one is of course pretty much
the opposite of the risk entry we have
higher probabilities because we have
confirmations we have lower trade
frequencies because we're going to miss
some trades you're going to have less
wins but you're also going to have less
losses if you've got a lower risk
tolerance this is going to be the
approach for you now to take a look at
the potential performance then on the
first trade we have an
8.53% potential return on the second
trade we have a
9.31 so we actually make around 0.8%
more on this second Opportunity by the
way the trades are not always going to
be this big these are some very healthy
looking trades because we were given a
large range to work with anything over
3% is good you don't always have to be
going for eight or 9 and I recommend you
don't don't always go for that work
dynamically with what the market
provides if it's a big one like this
that's all good if it's a three or then
that is also going to be completely fine
okay so as you can see we make more
money on the confirmation because of the
refined stop-loss but there was also the
opportunity that we missed this if we
didn't get this confirmation that we
wanted to see we wouldn't have caught
this trade and we also missed the
initial execution which means we would
have had to wait maybe a day or two more
yeah another day to actually find this
execution okay the first one's taken on
the 21st the second one didn't come
through until the 22nd so more patience
is required but you will have that
higher probability lower frequency
approach if you do opt for confirmations
okay so now looking at where the market
is currently sitting we haven't yet had
a real solid breakthrough of this low so
we don't really want to place any sell
orders yet the reason I say this is
although there is a very light closure
there is an immediate reversal and there
is only Wicks closing under this low so
this could potentially be what we call a
liquidity sweep which could lead into a
potential full-blown reversal for us to
start assessing new positions we would
want to see a nice closure through these
lows to confirm that this downtrend is
in action and then we can look for our
opportunities to sell into this
continuing
move so we do get a little closure there
which is good to see if we take a look
at the existing trending price action we
see that this area is our current Range
High we have an open are area of Supply
potentially there this didn't really
break any significant structure until we
formed this High which is now broken
through so what we can do at this point
is look towards
this Supply Zone this is the supply Zone
that has broken structure and led us
into a new downtrend the idea here would
be we could consider looking for shorts
from
here and then if the market was to break
higher we may then potentially have
buying
opportunities through the range until we
meet some of the higher Supply areas
such as here and such as here now for
continuation trades obviously we want to
move with the typ flow this means if we
do break Above This high that we've just
formed it's likely that we get some
shorter term buying opportunities at
least towards some of the open ranges
above so I'd be happy to look for shorts
from where we are given that we can get
a good enough Target uh let's just see
how the market flows for now see if we
can print any more of a significant low
okay we may have printed a low here no
we still have some ground to move okay
so we have a significant low printed at
this point this is all realistically
what I would classify as one leg of
price action because we've just got a
pretty solid movement down so we're
going to look at two approaches once
again for a short here see what we can
get in terms of risk reward for a sell
limit
opportunity so if we have our stop- loss
just above the swing High we're looking
at around a
3.37% potential return there once again
here here what do we have imbalance
there Supply there and then our swing
low Target here for our entry in a
predominantly down trending market so we
could place a sell limit here and we
will also assess for the confirmation
style entry once the market reaches into
this point so let's go ahead and place
this order that's what we did last time
and then we will track this from a
confirmation perspective as well without
actually placing in order and see the
outcome of each approach as we say if
this trade gets stopped out we may be
leading into buying territory to take
the market higher towards some of the
other open and balance Supply zones that
we have or maybe even into a full-blown
reversal past the previous high so for
now we'll focus on shorts but one thing
you need to understand when you are
trading from a um continuation
perspective is eventually your trade is
going to get destroyed okay the market
will at some point push and break
through your high if you're selling and
you will eventually lead into a losing
trade that is just how trading is and
that is just the natural flow of the
market market right for us to really
validate a short here we need to see a
break of this low so if we're go for
confirmations this is the kind of
movement that we would want to see okay
we're tagged in on our initial execution
now which is
good taking a look at the price action
here the high time frame Supply was
retested with this small indecision
candle here and we can see that there is
some inefficiency towards that area of
Supply okay so there's still a very tin
tiny amount of imbalance just in there
this even though it's just a tiny piece
of imbalance is definitely something
that I will always consider tiny
imbalances like that can actually get
filled and will usually get filled not
all of the time but a lot of the time so
that is where I would be looking for
shorts so if we were looking for a sell
here now that we're following this
confirmation we would have our sell
limit on this High we could have stops
above that Supply Zone high and targets
down into the low cuz at this point
we've validated and we've also kind of
validated that there's no reason for us
to go higher inside of this trend so
let's actually
see okay we've been tagged on
that be nice if this runs down to our
targets
now well that was a very fast one and uh
there you go we've been taken out at the
full take profit so this second
opportunity there you can see the
importance of looking at those
imbalances there is no imbalance above
in this price range there's no reason
for the Market to return to here unless
it's going to break through the highs we
see this very very small amount of
imbalance initially I didn't see it and
I believed that this was going to be the
supply we'd sell from but when you note
this tiny imbalance between the supply
and the wick we understand there's a
high likelihood that that's going to be
filled which allowed us of course to get
this second opportunity so once again
let's stack these up in terms of the two
sell limit risk entry trades we've taken
which is of course this one here and
then the first position over here we
looked at an 8.53% return on the first
one and a 3.37% return on on the second
one which leaves us with an 11.84 7%
return over these two positions which is
very very good obviously as I say
eventually this is going to blow the
other way and we will lose a trade most
likely but for now we are moving
naturally with the flow and we've caught
two really nice trades there from a sell
limit perspective fortunately both of
these trades did provide confirmation
entries the second one has returned
5.38% the first one returned
9.31 so we're looking at around 14.69%
return over those two confirmation
trades so the confirmations have
actually been more profitable than the
sell limits but of course they've been
trickier to catch and if you didn't have
the eye for the market or you missed
these opportunities of actually getting
in with the right confirmational
location then you would have missed the
trades and sometimes it's just going to
completely not form right sometimes we
are just going to sell off without
providing confirmations for those safer
kind of fractal entries so it really
depends on your risk tolerances and
which approach you prefer to take me
personally I am quite a big fan of these
confirmation approaches you get refined
stop- losses you get better risk reward
and you have higher probability so it's
a lot less stressful to hold a trade
that's double confirmed but the sell
limits are fine too and there are times
where I will take these positions over
the confirmational approaches now we
have come and wicked through this low
we've had no closures so we ideally need
to see a new closure under this low to
lead into a Next Movement so so now
let's continue the market through and
see if that
happens okay at this point we've broken
higher we just had a big push higher
that's pushed us above uh the previous
structural points realistically it's
going to be this one so that kind of
puts an end to our selling movements
okay this is going to lead into now most
likely reversal opportunities where the
market is likely to go the other way
which realistically brings an end to our
session inside of this bearish
continuation Trend Okay so we've had two
trades in two different scenarios with
between 11.8 and 14.6% potential Returns
on those trades you are going to lose
trades too you're going to get caught in
the mess sometimes the market will
sharply reverse on you sometimes and you
will of course just get burned but the
risk reward we're getting here and the
fact that it's so simple to just trade
through a natural market cycle like a
downtrend or an uptrend makes this a
very very nice way to trade and
hopefully over these examples I've
showed you how we do that okay so taking
a look at the analytics on this very
small sample size of continuation
trading we made 11.84 7% which is
$1,847 on a $100,000 account we only had
two trades but the average risk reward
across those trades was 5.95 and the
ideal average risk reward was 7.86 now
our maximum risk reward on one of the
trades was 8.53 the other one was just
over 3% as we saw there was potential to
run this to around 14% across the two
trades had you gone for the confirmation
based approaches the only big thing I
want to look at here is the monticolo
simulation to see how this system May
perform over a long term now you might
want to do and you probably well
definitely do want to do more samples
than two single positions what we're
going to do is put the win rate to
around 50% because this is the way that
I trade and my win rates are very close
to 50% long term meaning I win one trade
and I lose one trade so every 100 trades
I take I got 50 wins and 50 losses okay
now average loss of course is going to
be
$1,000 we'll leave the average gain
we'll leave the standard balance and
what we will do is do five different
simulations with let's do 100 trades
each so let's say we were to take a
trade let's do 250 so we took a trade
every single day of the year using this
system every single trading day that is
we have 50% losses and 50% wins this is
what your performance may look like if
you weren't to withdraw a single penny
and you were to compound your profits
okay now I would say your concerns are
not going to be this big number one
because you're going to pay yourself
right so there are going to be times
where you actually take money out of the
account uh this is if you just
compounded everything and number two you
probably don't want to compound your
risk percentage at least most people
won't because that is of course where
you get into the bounds of you know
risking $5,000 per trade here and you've
never actually paid yourself from your
system so we don't really care too much
about the actual numbers these are quite
optimistic but what we should focus on
is the the fact that every single one of
these simulations and even let's run 50
simulations is running positive okay so
every single one of these has ended the
250 trade period in positive profit none
of them have even any opportunity of
going bearish due to the fact that we
have positive risk reward working in our
favor now let's say our average gain was
actually around $3,000 so our average
trades were 3,000 3% and the trades
we've taken here which just outliers you
will still see with this approach that
after 250 trades it is practically
impossible providing you follow the
system to actually lose because at this
point you have positive risk reward
weighted in your favor you lose one
trade and lose 1% then you win one trade
and win 3% so every two trade you take
is averaging you 2% in returns you're
making 1% per trade essentially over
however many trades you take using this
continuation system so this is a great
way to trade okay once again don't worry
too much about the optimistic numbers
because chances are you're not going to
Triple or quadruple your account over
the span of a year you're not going to
be compounding your returns potentially
and most likely you are going to be
getting paid out especially if you're
working with a prop firm because they
will pretty much force you to take
payouts as well uh instead of running up
numbers like this if you want some help
to build out a continuation trading
strategy check out the top Link in the
description I have a completely free
seven-part course seven steps of
profitable trades I show you how to
build a trading stratey y from scratch
and how you can build upon that system
to improve your trading abilities so
that ultimately you can get consistent
get funded and make some money so check
that out it's 100% free if you don't
want to do that there's another video
somewhere on the screen right now thanks
for watching and I'll see you in the
next video